nautorswan.com 2016-05-16

# Nautor's Swan

## NAUTOR HOLDING - PRIVACY POLICY

Legislative Decree 196 of June 30, 2003 (Data Protection Code) 

In conformity with Article 13 of Legislative Decree 196, we wish to inform you that Nautor Holding Srl processes the personal data of its customers and those who have voluntarily provided their registration data, directly or by telephone, fax or email to our office. 

In conformity with the law (Article 2 - Purposes), Nautor Holding Srl guarantees that your personal data will be processed with respect for the rights, fundamental liberties and dignity of the interested party, with particular reference to confidentiality, personal identity and the right to the protection of personal data. 

### Purposes for which personal data is processed

All data provided by interested parties are exclusively processed to fulfill obligations related to the company's business and, in particular: 

  * to enter registration data in the company's computer database;
  * to calculate internal statistics;
  * preparing technical service sheets for support and/or training;
  * to issue delivery documents, invoices and credit memos;
  * issuing quotations and proposals to active and/or potential clients;
  * to issue requests for quotations and proposals to active and/or potential suppliers;
  * to process ordinary and VAT accounting;
  * to process collections and payments;
  * to send commercial and promotional information about its activities, or those of its connected companies to active and/or potential clients;
  * to exchange information about the company's economic, administrative and sales activities by telephone, mail, shipping companies, fax, e-mail and the private areas of the web site of Nautor Holding Srl;
  * to satisfy obligations envisaged by law, regulations, Community directives and the civil and tax codes;

### Communication and diffusion of data

If necessary, the personal data of interested parties can also be communicated: 

  * to all subjects who are legally entitled to access the data;
  * to our collaborators, employees and agents in the context of their relative duties and/or any contractual obligations with them, related to the commercial relationship with interested parties;
  * to companies that produce and/or grant licenses to use any services/products supplied, only when the communication is necessary for the use of the services/products purchased by the interested party;
  * to post offices, shipping companies and couriers for sending documentation and/or materials;
  * to suppliers of Unified Messaging services via the Internet, when this channel is used to send letters and messages to interested parties;
  * to all those physical and/or legal entities, both public and private (the offices of legal, administrative and tax consultants, the offices of payroll services, judicial offices, chambers of commerce and labor offices, etc.), when the communication is necessary or functional for our activities and in the manner and for the purposes described above;
  * to all those physical and/or legal entities, both public and private (the offices of legal, administrative and tax consultants, the offices of payroll services, judicial offices, chambers of commerce and labor offices, etc.), when the communication is necessary or functional for our activities and in the manner and for the purposes described above;

### Nature of the collection and the consequences of any failure to provide

For those who intend to open a commercial relationship with our company, even if purely for the purpose of obtaining information about our activities/services, providing personal data is optional; however, a failure to provide the information could make it impossible to continue the relationship, conduct it properly or fulfill legal and even tax obligations. The data are kept at our company's operating headquarters for the time required by civil and tax regulations. 

### Processing methods

The personal data is exclusively processed at the headquarters of Nautor Holding Sr, using both the telephone and computers and even using automated equipment for the storage, handling and transmission of the data, taking every precaution to guarantee its security and confidentiality. 

### Personal data controller for processing purposes

The owner of the personal data for processing purposes is Nautor Holding Srl. 

At present, the data processing manager is the President of Nautor Holding Srl. 

### Place of processing

The personal data collected through the online services provided by Nautor Holding Srl and the other Group companies will be held and stored in Florence, Borgo SS. Apostoli 29. 

All personal information is processed exclusively by technical staff specifically employed for this purpose and, occasionally, by maintenance personnel. 

### The right of access to personal data

The interested party has the right to know whether or not personal data about him exists, even if not yet recorded, and to receive a copy in intelligible form. 

The interested party has the right to know:

  * the origin, purposes and processing methods of the personal data;
  * the logic applied, in the case of processing by computers;
  * the contact information of the owner, managers and representative designated under article 5, paragraph 2, of Legislative Decree 196/2003;
  * the subjects, or categories of subjects, to whom the personal data may be communicated, or that may come to know it in their capacity as designated representative in the territory of the state, managers or appointees;

The interested party has the right to:

  * have the data updated, corrected or, when there is an interest, supplemented;
  * the cancellation, transformation into anonymous form or blockage of data processed in violation of the law, including that whose preservation is not necessary in relation to the purposes for which the data was collected or subsequently processed;

The interested party has the right to oppose, in whole or in part:

  * the processing of personal data that regards him, even though pertinent to the purpose for which it was gathered, for legitimate reasons;
  * the processing of personal data that regards him for the purpose of sending advertising or direct sales material or for market research or commercial communications;

The above rights may be exercised by an informal request to the owner and will be acknowledged without delay. A request may be sent to the owner via registered letter, fax or e-mail.

### Article 7

(Right of access to personal data and other rights)

  * 1\. The interested party has the right to know whether or not personal data about him exists, even if not yet recorded, and to receive a copy in intelligible form.;
  * 2\. The interested party has the right to know:
  * a) the origin of the personal data;
  * b) the purposes and methods of its processing;
  * c) the logic applied, in the case of processing by computers;
  * d) the contact information for the owner, managers and representative designated under article 5, paragraph 2;
  * e) the subjects, or categories of subjects, to whom the personal data may be communicated, or that may come to know it in their capacity as designated representative in the territory of the state, managers or appointees;
  * 3\. The interested party has the right to:
  * a) have the data updated, corrected or, when there is an interest, supplemented;
  * b) the cancellation, transformation or blockage of data handled in violation of the law, including that which it is not necessary to preserve in relation to the purposes for which the data was gathered or subsequently handled;
  * c) certification that the operations in letters "a" and "b" were brought to the attention, also as regards their content, of those to whom the data was communicated or published, except in the case where such fulfillment is impossible or involves a use of means that is obviously disproportionate to the right protected;
  * 4\. The interested party has the right to oppose, in whole or in part:
  * a) the processing of personal data that regards him, even though pertinent to the purpose for which it was gathered, for legitimate reasons;
  * b) the handling of personal data that regards him for the purpose of sending advertising or direct sales material or for market research or commercial communications;

## NAUTOR HOLDING - COOKIES

### Treatment of personal data - Cookies

Access to some sections of this website, including requests for information by the user may require the insertion of personal data which will be processed by Nautor Holding Srl, the data controller, is in compliance with the Legislative Decree 30 June 2003, No. 196 "Code concerning the protection of personal data." 

The release of personal information is a free choice of every user to this website. There is no other record of personal data without notification. 

In order to allow the activate specific functions, the Site may use cookies in some instances. The user may, by choice, be informed or prevent the use of such tools by modifying ones navigation settings.
